# 三叔 今儿初四了
San Shu, today is the fourth day of Lunar New Year.
# 为了咱吃这顿馅儿饼 老爷子准备了一早上
Lao Ye Zi (Beijing Slang - to call elder gentleman who is very close to you) was preparing ingredients whole morning so as we can have this pie.
# 这牛肉馅儿很鲜 肥瘦相间
The beef mince is very fresh and marbled (fat and thin).
# 他今天做的二八 二是肥八是瘦
He is using 20% fat and 80% lean today.
# 现在我和面呢  这面比饺子面呢稍微软点
I am making the dough right now. The dough should be a little bit softer than dumpling wrappers’ dough.
# 要薄皮大馅
We need thin skin and lots of stuffing.
# 皮要讲究焦黄外焦
The skin of the pie needs to be golden outside,
# 肉馅是里嫩 要吃这牛肉的香味
and stuffing is tender inside, it is particular about the taste of aroma of beef meat.
# 来点姜鲜姜
(I) need some ginger, fresh ginger.
# 盐 四克盐别太咸
Salt, four grams of salt. Not too salty.
# 搁点熟酱
Add more Shu Jiang (cooked soybean paste)
# 这熟酱是蒸熟的吗
Is this one steamed?
# 这是买来的 处理好的
I bought it. It has been taken care.
# 然后先上劲儿
Mixing the meat mince to be glutinous
# 一个方向啊 顺时针
following one direction, clockwise rotation.
# 一定要粘
It needs to be glutinous.
# 已经有点抱团了 直说咱不加鸡蛋 知道吧
It starts to stick together. We always say we don’t want to add eggs, you know?
# 好吃不好吃成不成肉饼都在这打馅儿上
Meat stuffing tends to be the crucial part of delicious pie.
# 机器能替代吗
Can we use machine to do the job?
# 可以啊 但是手工香
Sure. But hand-made (stuffing) is more delicious.
# 今天都是手打 他管我叫武手长
It is all hand-made today. He called me Wu Shou Zhang (Joke, hand and captain has the same pronunciation)
# 手长好
Aye, aye Captain.
# 同志们辛苦了
Comrades, thank you for your hard work!
# 为人民服务
Serve the people!
# 好好干
Keep your good work!
# 这牛肉馅儿真不能凑合
We can’t make do with beef stuffing.
# 直接上手吧
Just use your hand.
# 老冯开始玩真的了 陆续开始有点劲儿了
Lao Feng starts to be serious, it starts to be glutinous.
# 我觉得行了老爷子
I think it is okay now. Lao Ye Zi (Beijing slang – call an elder gentleman when you have a very close relationship with him)
# 下油了
Add oil
# 油得倒多少
How much?
# 一两 要不不出油
One Liang (50 grams), otherwise, the meat can't produce extra oil.
# 酱油 好嘞
Soy Sauce. Here we go!
# 我看一眼 好 冰箱里冻一下
Let me have a look. Perfect. Put in the fridge to freeze a little bit.
# 因为打的待会要出汁 所以要冻一下
Freezing the stuffing a little bit can help with producing more meat juice during blending.
# 牛肉馅儿和好了之后放大葱
When the meat stuffing is ready, we need to add some spring onions in.
# 这个馅儿里放四分之一
Put ¼ in to the stuffing.
# 放点香油 主要是借味
Add some sesame oil, just for the flavour.
# OK 好啦
OK.
# 老头还OK了现在
Our old pal starts to say OK now.
# 再来点胡椒粉
Add some pepper powder.
# 差不多了吧
Should be right.
# 跟擀饺子皮一样吗
Should I roll the dough like dumpling wrappers?
# 擀薄点
Thinner.
# 差不多了
Almost.
# 一定要这压住 蹭一下
This part needs to be pressed.
# 圈上 一会儿就会
Circle it. You can learn how to do it very fast.
# 要不拿擀面杖敲两下
Should we punch it by rolling pin?
# 严肃点别乐
Be serous, don’t laugh.
# 你看一弄打卷
Look this, you can make a roll.
# 进步大了 都会转了
Great improvement, you can whirl it.
# 我给你擀一个
Let me show you.
# 你看见没有 他手是圈的 这手一定要圈上
Do you see it? His hand is circling it, your hand needs to circle it.
# 看见没有
Do you see it?
# 三叔什么都会 我有点骄傲
San Shu can make everything. I am proud of him.
# 有点膨胀怎么什么都会呢
I am conceited that I can do everything.
# 怎没人夸我啊
Why no one compliments on my work?
# 特别好 不是一般的
Excellent! Not just fine.
# 包了啊
Let’s start.
# 别擀了 赶紧学 看看怎么包
Stop rolling, hurry up to learn, learn how to make pies.
# 这是关键了
This is the key point.
# 我这大拇哥是不进去的看见没有
My thumb is not inside, see?
# 他兜出来一小碗
He make the dough like a small bowl.
# 看见没有
See?
# 烙馅饼之前先给它捏成提褶包子
The predecessor of pie is actually Bao Zi (bun with wrinkles)
# 忌讳什么 半路出汤
What’s our taboo? Leaking at halfway.
# 坚决不能出汤
Leaking is not acceptable.
# 不是这种动 要搓
Not like this, twisting (rubbing with hands)
# 底下动 上面不动
Move the bottom not upside.
# 你看见没有 他是底下动
Don't you see? He just moves the downside.
# 我来一个
Let me make one.
# 我是直接就封口了
I’ll cover it up directly.
# 但是他大拇哥要搁里边儿 他是这样我是这样
But his thumb is inside, he is like this. My way is like this.
# 这是馅饼 看见没有
This is pie. See?
# 三叔什么不会啊
Is there anything San Shu couldn’t make?
# 怎么了这小褶 二十三个褶啊
What’s wrong with these pleats/wrinkles? 23 in total.
# 大家伙互相学习 互相进步
We are learning from each other so we can all improve.
# 一定不能拿掌心去拍 反面
Never pat it with palm. The other side.
# 烙饼其实很讲究 烙饼需要一口好的饼铛
We need to devote particular care to pie and flatbread. We need a good baking pan.
# 底要厚 加热的温度好掌握
The base should be think. Easier to master temperature.
# 这什么油啊 怎么这么黄啊
What kind of oil is this? So yellow.
# 最好的菜籽油
Best canola oil.
# 放点水
Add some water.
# 因为咱们的肉饼比较厚 咱们让熟的更透一点
As our beef pie is thinker, we are cooking it well-done.
# 这水呀一没 饼就得了
The pie is well-done once water is evaporated
# 今天咱们这馅饼已经做熟了
Now the pie is well-done.
# 老爷子最高之处你知道在哪吗
Do you know what is the brilliant method from Lao Ye Zi?
# 出锅前点的几滴香油
Sprinkle some sesame oil before take it out from baking pan.
# 老爷子一伸手就变成人间美味了
Delicious dishes are born with these hands of Lao Ye Zi.
# 咱们切开一个 看看这汁儿
Let’s slice one, take a look at this juicy stuffing.
# 这样切看见没有 拉着走
See how I slice it? Pull it.
# 看这汁儿 好不好
Look at this juicy. Nice or not?
# 有点像吃意大利肉饼的感觉
It tastes like Italian meat pie.
# 你看里头牛肉
Take a look at the beef inside.
# 皮薄馅儿大味厚而不咸
Thin skin, rich and tasty but not salty.
# 牛肉的香味冲上天
The aroma of the beef is so sharp.
# 照一百岁活
Live to be hundred.
# 我努力
I’ll try.
# 瞧瞧我的吧 看
Look at mine! Take a look!
# 肉颗粒感很强
Meat particle can be tasted.
# 牛肉馅儿饼第一次吃这么香的
This is the tasty and best beef pie I ever had.
# 老爷子哭了啊
Lao Ye Zi bursts into tears.
# 要传承 咱们就没有保守
# 一定要找出老的味道
We want to find the ancient taste.
# 希望您常出手
Wish you can cook more often.
# 继续努力
Keep making great efforts.
# 祝我们的新春佳节大家快乐高兴美食第一
Wish happy lunar new year with delicious tasty feast to us!
“我是大爷” 00:05:32.12